armadamarkets.com 2018-09-06

# For Clients

                                                                                      Privacy Policy
                                                                                                                               Tickmill Ltd
                                                                                                                                                             May 2018
                                                                                                       For Clients
Ti ckmill is the trading name of Tickmill Ltd Seychelles, regulated as a Secu rities Dealer by the Financial Services Authority of Seychelles with license number
                 (SD008) a nd the Pri ncipal office at: Trop-X Securities Exchange Building, 3, F28-F29 Eden Plaza, Eden Island, Mahe, Seychelles.
                                                                                                                                                                    1

Important information
  In line with Article 24 GDPR (EU) 2016/679, taking into account the nature, scope, context and
  purposes of processing as well as the risks to the rights and freedoms of natural persons, Tickmill
  Ltd have implemented appropriate technical and organisational measures to ensure pursuance to
  the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). This policy stands as the cornerstone to Tickmill
  Ltd’s compliance with the GDPR and is reviewed and updated accordingly.
  This Policy that provides data subjects with information on how Tickmill Ltd collects personal data,
  what they do with it and with whom it may be shared. This privacy notice has been drafted in
  compliance with the requirements of the General Data Protection Regulation, Regulation (EU)
  2016/679, (the GDPR) and on the basis of the Information Commissioner’s Code of Practice on
  ‘Privacy notices, transparency and control’ and the Article 29 European Commission Guidelines on
  transparency under the GDPR.
 Ti ckmill is the trading name of Tickmill Ltd Seychelles, regulated as a Secu rities Dealer by the Financial Services Authority of Seychelles with license number
                  (SD008) a nd the Pri ncipal office at: Trop-X Securities Exchange Building, 3, F28-F29 Eden Plaza, Eden Island, Mahe, Seychelles.
                                                                                                                                                                   2

We ask that you read this privacy notice carefully as we would like to inform you that your privacy
on the internet is of crucial importance to us and it also contains important information on who we
are, how and why we collect, store, use and share personal information, your rights in relation to
your personal information and on how to contact us and supervisory authorities in the event you
have a complaint.
Who we are
Tickmill Ltd (“Tickmill”, “us”, “our” or “we”) collects, uses and is responsible for certain personal
information about you. When we do so we are regulated under the General Data Protection
Regulation which applies across the European Union (including in the United Kingdom) and we are
responsible as ‘controller’ of that personal information for the purposes of those laws.
The personal information we collect and use
Data Controllers and Contracting Parties
Regardless of whether you reside inside or outside the “Designated Countries”, Tickmill Ltd will be
the controller of your personal data provided to, or collected by or for, or processed in connection
with our services and regulated activities.
Whether information has to be provided by you, and if so why
The provision of “Your Data” (please see next paragraph) is required from you to enable us to
provide our services. We will inform you at the point of collecting information from you, whether
you are required to provide the information to us.
Information collected by us
In the course of your registration as a client, signing up for a demo or a live account with Tickmill or
filling any other form on our Website, subscribing to our services, news or offers, marketing
communications or posting material, the following information about you (“Your Data”) will be
collected and stored for administrative, service related and/or legal purposes.
We will limit the collection of personal information to what is necessary to administer our business
and carry out our regulated activities in an effort to provide you with superior service.
Information that you provide to us directly:
      •        Personal information, such as names, addresses, personal registration number, national
               identification number, passport number and e-mail addresses etc (“Personal Information”).,
               and
      •        Financial information, trading experience and employment information for appropriateness
               assessment will also be collected.
               However, the meaning of data ‘provided to’ Tickmill is not limited to this. It is also personal
               data resulting from observation of your activities (eg where using a device or service).
               This may include:
 Ti ckmill is the trading name of Tickmill Ltd Seychelles, regulated as a Secu rities Dealer by the Financial Services Authority of Seychelles with license number
                  (SD008) a nd the Pri ncipal office at: Trop-X Securities Exchange Building, 3, F28-F29 Eden Plaza, Eden Island, Mahe, Seychelles.
                                                                                                                                                                   3

                       •     history of website usage or search activities, details of your visits to our Website
                             including, communication data
                       •     traffic and location data; or
                       •     website traffic pattern information, including IP addresses, operating system and
                             browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to our
                             advertisers. This kind of information is only used in masked or aggregated form,
                             which means that the individual user will not be recognisable. These data do not
                             identify any individual.
                       •     Communications between you and Tickmill via Live Chat, email, or telephone call.
  Your e-mail address may be used by Tickmill in relation to its products and services (including any
  marketing campaigns related to these products or services). If you do not wish to receive such
  marketing material and marketing communications, you can opt-out at any time by clicking on
  ‘unsubscribe’ or by sending an email stating so to support@tickmill.com.
  The type of data collected and purpose of collection
  The type of data we collect along with the purpose for collection is listed below:
Personal data type:                                                                Purpose:
Personal information such as gender, name,                                         To meet our anti money laundering (AML) and
date of birth and address                                                          other regulatory obligations in relation to Know
                                                                                   Your Client (KYC) and client due diligence. To
                                                                                   verify your identity using our verification
                                                                                   processes.
Contact information (email address and phone                                       In order to send you correspondence in
number)                                                                            relation to the services provided and to fulfil
                                                                                   our regulatory and compliance obligations
Employment information, financial                                                  In order to comply with KYC obligations and in
information, relevant education and trading                                        order to meet our regulatory obligations
experience                                                                         relating to assessing the appropriateness of our
                                                                                   products and services
Ethnicity, citizenship and social security                                         In order to comply with KYC and regulatory
numbers or national identity and passport                                          trade reporting and other AML obligations
numbers
Proof of photo ID, address verification                                            In order to comply with KYC and regulatory
                                                                                   trade reporting and other AML obligations
Unique device number (IP address) and device                                       When you visit our website, navigate through
information including version of web browser                                       the pages or fill in any forms, we may collect
you use                                                                            your unique device number or IP address in
                                                                                   order to set up your profile.
   Ti ckmill is the trading name of Tickmill Ltd Seychelles, regulated as a Secu rities Dealer by the Financial Services Authority of Seychelles with license number
                    (SD008) a nd the Pri ncipal office at: Trop-X Securities Exchange Building, 3, F28-F29 Eden Plaza, Eden Island, Mahe, Seychelles.
                                                                                                                                                                     4

Financial sanctions and credit header                                              In order to perform our electronic AML
information                                                                        screening checks and to comply with other
                                                                                   fraud detection policies. This may generate
                                                                                   further information on your credit history,
                                                                                   criminal convictions or political interests
                                                                                   leading to us making decisions based on the
                                                                                   results of these checks
  How we use your personal information
  We use information held about you in the following ways:
        •        to ensure that the content in our website is presented to you in the most effective manner
                 and to improve the content of our website.
        •        to communicate with you and contact you and to provide you with products and services
                 that you request from us or, where you have consented to be contacted, for products and
                 services that we feel may be of interest to you;
        •        managing and administering the products and services provided to you;
        •        keeping you updated as a client in relation to changes to our services and relevant matters;
        •        provide, improve, test, and monitor the effectiveness of our Services.
        •        develop and test new products and features.
        •        monitor metrics such as total number of visitors, traffic, and demographic patterns.
        •        diagnose or fix technology problems.
        •        to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered between you and us.
        •        we may also use your data, or permit selected third parties and our processors to use your
                 data, to provide you with information about goods and services which may be of interest to
                 you and we or they may contact you about these by email.
        •        to notify you about updates to the website.
        •        to send out newsletters or information about other opportunities that we believe will be of
                 interest to you. We will only send this to you if you have indicated that you wish to receive
                 such information and we will respect your wish not to do so if you communicate such wish
                 to us. You can opt-out from receiving marketing communications at any time if you do not
        •        wish to receive such marketing material by clicking on ‘unsubscribe’ or by sending an email
                 stating so to support@tickmill.com.
        •        to promote safety and security. We use the information we have to help verify accounts and
                 activity, and to promote safety and security on our regulated services, such as by
                 investigating suspicious activity or violations of our terms or policies. We work hard to
                 protect your account using teams of IT specialists, automated systems, and advanced
                 technology such as encryption.
   Ti ckmill is the trading name of Tickmill Ltd Seychelles, regulated as a Secu rities Dealer by the Financial Services Authority of Seychelles with license number
                    (SD008) a nd the Pri ncipal office at: Trop-X Securities Exchange Building, 3, F28-F29 Eden Plaza, Eden Island, Mahe, Seychelles.
                                                                                                                                                                     5

Who we share your personal information with?
We will not rent or sell your information to third parties outside Tickmill (or the group of companies
of which Tickmill is a part) without your consent. We also impose strict restrictions on how our
processors can use and disclose the data we provide. Here are the types of third parties we share
information with:
      •        Service providers and other partners: We transfer information to service providers
               (processors), and other partners who globally support our business, such as providing
               technical infrastructure services, trading platforms analysing how our Services are used such
               as measuring the effectiveness of ads and services, providing client service and support,
               client on-boarding, client identity verification, including PEPs and sanctions, conducting
               marketing communications and design, services related to our website management,
               services related to software and business development services.
               We may need to transfer personal data to recipients outside the European Union; these
               activities can include dealings with foreign public entities (only when necessary and under
               request), the outsourcing of services to external providers located outside the EU and/or
               processing the data outside the EU (e.g. cloud computing, client identity verification and
               individuals from outside the EEA accessing to our web-services), see paragraph Transfer of
               your information out of the EEA).
      •        Measurement and Analytics Services: Partners who use our analytics services like Google
               Analytics (Non-Personally Identifiable Information Only). We do not share information that
               personally identifies you (personally identifiable information is information like name or
               email address that can by itself be used to contact you or identifies who you are) with
               advertising, measurement or analytics partners.
Tickmill does extensive due diligence before choosing processors assuring that they provide
sufficient safeguards, in particular in terms of expert knowledge, data governance, data security,
cyber resilience, reliability and resources to implement technical and organisational measures which
will meet the requirements of this General Personal Data Regulation, including for the security of
processing.
We routinely share your personal data with our processor Tickmill Europe Ltd, which makes it
possible to operate our company, where processing is to be carried out on behalf of the controller
(us). Our processor provides sufficient safeguards to implement appropriate technical and
organisational measures in such a manner that processing will meet the requirements of General
Personal Data Regulation and ensure the protection of the rights of the data subject.
The adherence of the processor to a SLA Contract is used as an element to demonstrate compliance
with the obligations of the controller.
The carrying-out of processing by our processor it is governed by a contract or other legal act under
Union or Member State law, binding the processor to the controller (Tickmill Ltd).
This data sharing with our processor enables us to proceed with our regulated activities and duties
to KYC in order to meet our regulatory obligations relating to assess the appropriateness of our
products and services, provide support to clients, etc. Some of those third party recipients
(processors) may be based outside the European Economic Area; if the third party recipient is
located outside the EU/EEA in a country not ensuring an adequate level of data protection, the
transfer will only be completed if a written agreement has been entered into between Tickmill and
the third party. The written agreement shall be based on the Standard Contractual Clauses approved
 Ti ckmill is the trading name of Tickmill Ltd Seychelles, regulated as a Secu rities Dealer by the Financial Services Authority of Seychelles with license number
                  (SD008) a nd the Pri ncipal office at: Trop-X Securities Exchange Building, 3, F28-F29 Eden Plaza, Eden Island, Mahe, Seychelles.
                                                                                                                                                                   6

by the European Commission (and any updated versions). — for further information including on
how we safeguard your personal data when these cases occur, see paragraph ‘Transfer of your
information out of the EEA’.
We will share personal information with law enforcement or other authorities if required by
applicable law.
Cookie Data
We use cookies and similar technologies to provide and support our Services. When you use our
website we will use cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website.
For more information about cookies and how we use them, please read our Cookies Policy.
How our global services operate
Transfer of your information out of the EEA
Information collected within the European Economic Area (“EEA”) may, for example, be transferred
to countries outside of the EEA for the purposes described in this policy and relying on the lawful
basis of contractual necessity and compliance with our legal obligations.
 We and our processors when data is transferred outside the EEA utilise standard contract clauses
approved by the European Commission and we adopt other means under European Union law and
may obtain your consent to legitimise data transfers from the EEA to and other countries.
How do we respond to legal requests or prevent harm?
We access, preserve and share your information with regulators, law enforcement or others by
request:
      •        We can respond to legal requests when we have a good-faith belief that the response is
               required by law in that jurisdiction, affects users in that jurisdiction, and is consistent with
               internationally recognised standards.
      •        When we have a good-faith belief it is necessary to: detect, prevent and address fraud,
               unauthorised use of the services or products, violations of our terms or policies, or other
               harmful or illegal activity; to protect ourselves (including our rights, property or Products),
               you or others, including as part of investigations or regulatory inquiries; or to prevent death
               or imminent bodily harm. For example, if relevant, we provide information to and receive
               information from third-parties about the reliability of your account to prevent fraud, abuse
               and other harmful activity on and off our Products.
Information we receive about you (including financial transaction as data related to deposits and
withdrawals) can be accessed and preserved for an extended period when it is the subject of a legal
 Ti ckmill is the trading name of Tickmill Ltd Seychelles, regulated as a Secu rities Dealer by the Financial Services Authority of Seychelles with license number
                  (SD008) a nd the Pri ncipal office at: Trop-X Securities Exchange Building, 3, F28-F29 Eden Plaza, Eden Island, Mahe, Seychelles.
                                                                                                                                                                   7

request or obligation, governmental investigation, or investigations of possible violations of our
terms or policies, or otherwise to prevent harm. We also retain information from accounts disabled
for terms violations for at least a year to prevent repeat abuse or other term violations.
Your rights
Under the General Data Protection Regulation you have a number of important rights. In summary,
those include rights to:
      •        fair processing of information and transparency over how we use your use personal
               information,
      •        The right to access personal data: via a Subject Access Request. Your request should be made in
               writing to dpo@tickmill.eu and/or Tickmill Ltd: Trop-X Securities Exchange Building, 3, F28-F29
               Eden Plaza, Eden Island, Mahe, Seychelles. . We may ask you for proof of identity before providing
               you with the data. There is usually no charge for such requests, however in limited circumstances we
               may be able to charge an administrative fee (and we will inform you in response to your request if
               that is the case).
      •        The right to request that your personal data is corrected if it is found to be inaccurate:
               require us to correct any mistakes in your information which we hold.
      •        The right to request that your personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary. In
               some circumstances this right may not apply e.g. if there is some other compelling reason
               for us to keep or process your data (and we will inform you in response to your request if
               that is the case)
      •        Right to data portability: to receive the personal information concerning you which you have
               provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and have the
               right to transmit those data to a third party (another controller) in certain situations.
      •        The right to withdraw consent to processing at any time, where relevant i.e. where we are
               relying on your consent to process the data and not another legal reason for processing.
      •        The right to object at any time to processing of personal information concerning you for
               direct marketing.
      •        The right not to be subject to a decision which is based solely on automated processing,
               including profiling which produces legal effects concerning them or similarly significant
               affects them
      •        The right to object in certain other situations to our continued processing of your personal
               information.
      •        otherwise restrict our processing of your personal information in certain circumstances
For further information on each of those rights, including the circumstances in which they apply, see
the Guidance from the UK Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) on individuals rights under the
General Data Protection Regulation.
If you would like to exercise any of those rights, please:
      •        email, call or write to us at support@tickmill.com OR contact our Data Protection Officer at
               dpo@tickmill.eu.
 Ti ckmill is the trading name of Tickmill Ltd Seychelles, regulated as a Secu rities Dealer by the Financial Services Authority of Seychelles with license number
                  (SD008) a nd the Pri ncipal office at: Trop-X Securities Exchange Building, 3, F28-F29 Eden Plaza, Eden Island, Mahe, Seychelles.
                                                                                                                                                                   8

      •        let us have enough information to identify you (eg account number, user name, registration
               details),
      •        let us have proof of your identity and address (a copy of your driving licence or passport and
               a recent utility or credit card bill), and
      •        let us know the information to which your request relates, including any account or
               reference numbers, if you have them.
If you would like to unsubscribe from any emailing or any marketing communications you can also
click on the ‘unsubscribe’ button at the bottom of the email or by sending an email to
support@tickmill.com stating so.
Legal basis for processing personal data
Reasons we can collect and use your personal information: Lawful basis for
processing
Under EU data protection law, there must be a lawful basis for all processing of personal data (unless
an exemption or derogation applies). We rely on:
       • Contractual necessity
                 Processing is necessary for the performance of a contract with the data subject or to take
                steps to enter into a contract to conduct regulated activities, when processing is necessary
                for the entry into, or performance of contract with the data subject or in order to take steps
                at this or her request prior to the entry into a contract.
       • Compliance with legal obligations
                Processing is necessary for compliance with our legal obligation. Tickmill has the necessity
                for compliance with a legal obligation.
       • Legitimate interest
               Data will only be processed where it is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests
               pursued by Tickmill, and these interests or fundamental rights are not overridden by the
               interests, rights and freedoms of the data subject and that the processing would not cause
               unwarranted harm. For instance, it is a legitimate interest of Tickmill to process personal
               data on data subjects in order to expand the business, develop new business relations
               prevention of fraud, maintaining the security of our systems if/when necessary, enhancing,
               modifying or improving our services. The data subject must be given information on the
               specific legitimate interest if a processing is based on this provision.
 Ti ckmill is the trading name of Tickmill Ltd Seychelles, regulated as a Secu rities Dealer by the Financial Services Authority of Seychelles with license number
                  (SD008) a nd the Pri ncipal office at: Trop-X Securities Exchange Building, 3, F28-F29 Eden Plaza, Eden Island, Mahe, Seychelles.
                                                                                                                                                                   9

Keeping your personal information secure
Your Data is stored and kept confidential according to the legislation on protection of personal data
and processing thereof applicable in the jurisdiction in which Tickmill with which you have signed up
is located.
We have appropriate security measures in place to prevent personal information from being
accidentally lost, misused, modification, disclosure or accessed in an unauthorised way. We limit
access to your personal information to those who have a genuine business need to know it. Those
processing your information will do so only in an authorised manner and are subject to a duty of
confidentiality.
We also have procedures in place to deal with any suspected data security breach. We will notify
you and any applicable regulator of a suspected data security breach where we are legally required
to do so.
How long your personal information will be kept
Data retention:
You can close your account any time, but for audit trail purposes, Tickmill shall hold personal data
for a period of at least five years after closing the account in order for us to comply with our record
keeping obligations under the Money Laundering Regulations 2017.
At the end of that period, we will delete all personal data relating to you, unless a legal requirement
requires them to keep the data for a prolonged period of time, or Data Subject has expressly
consented to their data being held for an extended period of time.
What happens in the event of a change of control
If we sell or otherwise transfer part or the whole of Tickmill or our assets to another organization
(e.g., in the course of a transaction like a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy, dissolution, liquidation),
your information such as name and email address and any other information collected through the
Service may be among the items sold or transferred. You will continue to own your User Content.
The buyer or transferee will have to honour the commitments we have made in this Privacy Policy.
How to complain
We hope that our Data Protection Officer, client support or compliance team can resolve any query
or concern you raise about our use of your information.
The General Data Protection Regulation also gives you right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory
authority, in the Seychelles the Data Protection Act (the 'Act') was enacted in 2003 (Act No. 9 of
2003) with the aim of protecting the fundamental privacy rights of individuals against the use of data
concerning them without their informed consent. The Act will come into operation on such date as
the Minister notifies in the official Gazette.
 Ti ckmill is the trading name of Tickmill Ltd Seychelles, regulated as a Secu rities Dealer by the Financial Services Authority of Seychelles with license number
                  (SD008) a nd the Pri ncipal office at: Trop-X Securities Exchange Building, 3, F28-F29 Eden Plaza, Eden Island, Mahe, Seychelles.
                                                                                                                                                                   10

As of May 2015, the Act has not yet come into operation. In the European Union (or European
Economic Area) in the country (member state) where you work, normally live or where any alleged
infringement of data protection laws occurred.
How to contact us
If you wish to contact us with any queries, concerns or complaints, you can email us at
support@tickmill.com or write to: 1 Fore St. London EC2Y 9DT, United Kingdom or call us at +44
(0)20 3608 6100 or                           +44 (0)20 3608 2100 or contact our Data Protection Officer at
dpo@tickmill.com.
National requirements
Tickmill shall comply with both the GDPR and national data protection legislation.
If applicable national legislation requires a higher level of protection for personal data than such
policies/guidelines, such stricter requirements are to be complied with. If Tickmill policies/guidelines
are stricter than the local legislation, our policies/guidelines must be complied with.
Changes to this privacy notice
This privacy notice was published on May 2018 and last updated on May 2018.
We may change this privacy policy from time to time, when we do we will inform you via our
Website or via email.
Do you need extra help?
If you would like this notice in another format (for example: audio, large print, braille) please contact
us (see ‘How to contact us’ above).
 Ti ckmill is the trading name of Tickmill Ltd Seychelles, regulated as a Secu rities Dealer by the Financial Services Authority of Seychelles with license number
                  (SD008) a nd the Pri ncipal office at: Trop-X Securities Exchange Building, 3, F28-F29 Eden Plaza, Eden Island, Mahe, Seychelles.
                                                                                                                                                                   11
